okay um what would you is a question you
we showed you a couple of things
yesterday this is only for the video as
well we showed you the battery with the
spark not detona that and um we talked
about Val bounce because you're into
engines and so on like that as well we
talked about Val bounce and and the
concept of Val bounce okay Val bounce
itself is not Val bounce
hi folks this is Joe but you knew that
did that get on there I hope so no I
don't give that J bit because people
look at me face no it's not you but you
know that there's three of him this is
the other
third
um so um Veil bounce um and so on people
just don't understand it now it sounds
like it's right because if you have a
valve which is bouncing at um the soal
5,000 ribs it's not crashing either um
valve B valve crash valve whatever you
you want to call
it you went out that
way Peter yeah here
outside in here looking for you well I'm
only relating the terms that I heard
yeah heard and that's what most people
understand we going okay but it's not
really it's not really
a month ago it's
not
last sounds
[Applause]
like you're keep it
going I was always told
as it was turned was dangerous to an Eng
if you drop a valve stuck pist stuck the
heads you know what I mean most of the
valves broke because they were exceeding
their limits the head of the valve would
come off and hit the top of the
Piston that was it the C stay there the
valve stem stayed in the head I I saw a
head of a valve come off and hit the
pist do that or they can rip the collets
out of the top oh yeah I've seen that
there a l fit
you right yeah what I saw was a head
com do you want me to sit closer to no
no good day DG good
day and movie star and Trevor Trevor
good and even better looking oh
wonderful hands
up this is different okay um what Val V
really is is not that um and so what
actually happens is is um uh Roo for you
may not pick it up on here cam no no cam
sh can't keep up
no okay I'm not I don't want to jump the
gun I was just thinking that yeah no
that's fine well what that one you're
saying about the uh engine's got uh 10
cers working for the Dual spark the Dual
spark yeah uh could it be that you're
hearing and and you're thinking the
vales of answer no no does that happen
with all V6 Motors or is it just with
certain is it are they manufactured to
do that or is it a quance well no
commodor what they're talking about is
Waste spk Management which is double
firing the Commodore uses waste bark
management and waste bark management is
that you are using the negative side on
on a car out here in Australia you're
using the negative side of your coil to
put put your points in and that then
you're breaking the points and that then
gives you your spark out your coil to
fire your um you know your spark plug on
compression stroke yeah okay but um but
you see we were talking about this this
morning you've only got six pistons in a
in a six mon M right but you were saying
yesterday that you can get 12
Sparks yeah what they do is the commodor
use waste spark management now what
waste is it's not waste spark to start
with it is just waste is it burning the
gases that would go out the exhaust yeah
so I'll explain it so what what it is is
waste and they don't use the positive
side okay so that is what a normal car
doesn't use is the positive side of your
coil that just goes around your coil and
then goes back out of negative out the
negative side into ground that's what it
used to do okay now still does that but
what they do is on the negative side we
break those set of points and at the
breaking of the points sends the right
frequency charge with the condenser to
the coil and everything else and then
you get that spark coming out the top
now that spark is not um got nothing to
do with the positive or the negative in
the coil the coil just passes the
negative through and goes up the
positive wire the positive comes through
goes around and goes out the negative
okay so the the um spark going down to
your spark plugs is a 90° Spike it's a
new energy it's a new electricity it
doesn't use any of the positive or
negative to actually create it it is
created off the coil you know something
I've never heard have you heard of this
before Tesla's idea what he come up with
and that's your 90°
Spike okay you're not discharging
negative or positive to actually do it
you're setting up electromagnetic field
for a couple of coils you know primary
and secondary in the coil okay um that's
in the old coil with the oil in there
and everything now these later coils
they don't um do the same thing okay
they electronically break them
computerize everything else and they're
breaking actually the the um the um
spark but they're still getting a 90°
Spike right okay the coil is a coil no
matter what it is okay now the um what
the Commodore did in 1988 they used it
um here on the first VNS okay they had
it a bit before that but they used it
and they what they did was they also
broke the um positive wire with a
breaking like a set of points okay so
your normal point point if you break
them that's where it's lined up for your
timing and everything else to fire it
now when it closes it also um you know
sends a frequency does the same thing
but that one doesn't fire your engine
okay so now what they did was there the
commodor V6 is firing the um compression
chamber 6° before top dead center okay
now what they're doing is they the
positive is also flowing at the same
rate it's equal y negative and positive
are equal flow at the same time okay so
they actually break the positive as well
now that positive is opposite to
negative the negative is fired into the
compression chamber and the opposite of
that won't fire compression chamber so
they put it at 6° before top dead center
in the exhaust now the exhaust valve is
still open yeah your exhaust emissions
are escaping out but like a two- strike
a two- strike engine should not